

☑ clement.tamines@umons.ac.be | 🔏 clement.tamin.es | 🧿 My GitHub

Summary_

I am a PhD Candidate in the Computer Science department at the University of Mons (UMONS) in Belgium. I am co-supervised by Véronique Bruyère (UMONS) and Jean-François Raskin (Université libre de Bruxelles). My research interests regard equilibria in non-zero-sum multiplayer games and solving parity and generalized parity games. I am also very interested in the field of machine learning.

Education

University of Mons Mons, Belgium PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, expected graduation in September 2022. Oct. 2018 - Sept. 2022 University Certificate in Artificial Intelligence, graduated Magna Cum Laude. Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2020 Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2018 MASTER IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, graduated Summa Cum Laude. BACHELOR IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, graduated Cum Laude. Sept. 2013 - Aug. 2016

Research Experience

University of Mons Mons, Belgium

PHD CANDIDATE, SUPERVISED BY V. BRUYÈRE (UMONS) AND J.-F. RASKIN (ULB).

Oct. 2018 - Sept. 2022

• Equilibria in Multiplayer Games with Multiple Objectives.

TEACHING ASSISTANT Oct. 2018 - Aug. 2022

- Directed the project for the course Algorithmics and Bioinformatics (Java 8 program for DNA fragment assembly).
- Obtained very positive student evaluation (good to excellent).

ADVISOR Sept. 2018 - Aug. 2022

- Supervised 2 research internships on symbolic solving of games using Binary Decision Diagrams.
- Advised a Master student for a project on window techniques for solving parity games.

Sept. 2016 - May. 2018

• Tutored students for the Programming and Algorithmics I & II courses (Python 3 & Java 8).

Publications

- Véronique Bruyère, Jean-François Raskin, and Clément Tamines. Stackelberg-Pareto Synthesis. In Serge Haddad and Daniele Varacca, editors, 32nd International Conference on Concurrency Theory, CONCUR 2021, August 24-27, 2021, Virtual Conference, volume 203 of LIPIcs, pages 27:1–27:17. Schloss Dagstuhl - Leibniz-Zentrum für Informatik, 2021.
- Véronique Bruyère, Guillermo A. Pérez, Jean-François Raskin, and Clément Tamines. Partial Solvers for Generalized Parity Games. In Reachability Problems - 13th International Conference, RP 2019, Brussels, Belgium, September 11-13, 2019, Proceedings, pages 63-78, 2019.

Work Experience _____

Software Developer Intern

Tubize, Belgium

Sept. 2017 - Nov. 2017 THALES BELGIUM SA.

• Designed and implemented a constraint programming model for network generation in a radio configuration tool (Java 8 and Choco Solver).

Programming Skills _____

Tensorflow (Keras), Scikit-learn, OpenAl Gym, Jupyter Notebook, PyTest Pvthon

Cloud service Google Colaboratory, FloydHub Swing, JUnit, Choco Solver

Tools Git, Maven, JetBrains suite, Eclipse

Languages

French Native proficiency.

English Full professional proficiency (C1 level - TOEIC 2021).

Dutch Notions (looking to improve).

Talks & Attended Research Events.

TALKS (8)

2021	Stackelberg-Pareto Synthesis, Highlights'21, held online	Aachen, Germany
2021	Stackelberg-Pareto Synthesis, CONCUR'21, held online	Paris, France
2021	Stackelberg-Pareto Synthesis, MFV Seminar	Brussels, Belgium
2020	Formal Verification Using Games, Youth Seminar	Mons, Belgium
2019	Partial Solvers for Generalized Parity Games, Highlights'19	Warsaw, Poland
2019	Partial Solvers for Generalized Parity Games, RP'19	Brussels, Belgium
2019	Partial Solvers for Generalized Parity Games, MoRe'19	Vancouver, Canada
2019	Your Turn to Play!, Math & Science Days'19	Mons, Belgium

EVENTS (20)

2021CONCUR 2021: 32nd International Conference on Concurrency Theory, CONCUR'21, held onlineParis, France2021SYNT 2021: 10th Workshop on Synthesis, CAV'21 workshop, held onlineLos Angeles, USA2021Reinforcement Learning: from Theory to Practice, summer schoolonline2021Theoretical Foundations of Computer Systems Boot Camp, seminarsonline2020GandALF: Games, Automata, Logics, and Formal Verification, GandALF'20online2020Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'20online2020Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer schoolonline2020Dynamics and Information, workshopTel Aviv, Israel2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19Warsaw, Poland201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2018Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany2018Logic and Learning, FoPSS summer schoolOxford, UK	2021	Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'21, held online	Aachen, Germany
2021Reinforcement Learning: from Theory to Practice, summer schoolonline2021Theoretical Foundations of Computer Systems Boot Camp, seminarsonline2020GandALF: Games, Automata, Logics, and Formal Verification, GandALF'20online2020Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'20online2020Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer schoolonline2020Dynamics and Information, workshopTel Aviv, Israel2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19Warsaw, Poland201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2018Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2021	CONCUR 2021: 32nd International Conference on Concurrency Theory, CONCUR'21, held online	Paris, France
2021Theoretical Foundations of Computer Systems Boot Camp, seminarsonline2020GandALF: Games, Automata, Logics, and Formal Verification, GandALF'20online2020Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'20online2020Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer schoolonline2020Dynamics and Information, workshopTel Aviv, Israel2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19Warsaw, Poland201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2021	SYNT 2021: 10th Workshop on Synthesis, CAV'21 workshop, held online	Los Angeles, USA
2020GandALF: Games, Automata, Logics, and Formal Verification, GandALF'20online2020Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'20online2020Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer schoolonline2020Dynamics and Information, workshopTel Aviv, Israel2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19Warsaw, Poland201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2021	Reinforcement Learning: from Theory to Practice, summer school	online
2020Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'20online2020Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer schoolonline2020Dynamics and Information, workshopTel Aviv, Israel2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19Warsaw, Poland201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2021	Theoretical Foundations of Computer Systems Boot Camp, seminars	online
2020Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer schoolonline2020Dynamics and Information, workshopTel Aviv, Israel2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19Warsaw, Poland201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2020	GandALF: Games, Automata, Logics, and Formal Verification, GandALF'20	online
2020Dynamics and Information, workshopTel Aviv, Israel2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19Warsaw, Poland201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2020	Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'20	online
Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19 Warsaw, Poland 13th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19 Brussels, Belgium LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshop Wancouver, Canada MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshop Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizer MoC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research event CFV, seminars Brussels, Belgium MFV, seminars Brussels, Belgium	2020	Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer school	online
201913th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19Brussels, Belgium2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2020	Dynamics and Information, workshop	Tel Aviv, Israel
2019LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2019	Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'19	Warsaw, Poland
2019MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshopVancouver, Canada2019Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizerMons, Belgium2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2018Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2019	13th International Conference on Reachability Problems, RP'19	Brussels, Belgium
Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizer Mons, Belgium Mons, Belgium Mons, Belgium CFV, seminars Brussels, Belgium MFV, seminars Brussels, Belgium	2019	LearnAut: Learning and Automata, LICS'19 workshop	Vancouver, Canada
2019MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research eventMons, Belgium2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2018Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2019	MoRe: Multi-objective Reasoning in Verification and Synthesis, LICS'19 workshop	Vancouver, Canada
2019CFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2019MFV, seminarsBrussels, Belgium2018Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18Berlin, Germany	2019	Theory and Algorithms in Graph and Stochastic Games, co-organizer	Mons, Belgium
2019 MFV, seminars Brussels, Belgium 2018 Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18 Berlin, Germany	2019	MdC: Mardi des Chercheurs, UMONS research event	Mons, Belgium
2018 Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata , Highlights'18 Berlin, Germany	2019	CFV, seminars	Brussels, Belgium
	2019	MFV, seminars	Brussels, Belgium
2018 Logic and Learning , FoPSS summer school Oxford, UK	2018	Highlights of Logic, Games and Automata, Highlights'18	Berlin, Germany
	2018	Logic and Learning, FoPSS summer school	Oxford, UK
2018 Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes , MOVEP summer school <i>Cachan, France</i>	2018	Modelling and Verification of Parallel Processes, MOVEP summer school	Cachan, France

${\bf Extracurricular\,Activity}_$

Activities and Societies Mons, Belgium

University of Mons

Sept. 2015 - Aug. 2018

- Managed communications for the General Association of Science Students.
- Represented students in the Faculty of Science Council.

Student JobsMons, Belgium

University of Mons

Sept. 2015 - Aug. 2018

- Guided and informed people through campus during open days.
- Informed people and promoted the faculty during student fairs (SIEP).